<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/project.xsl"?>

<projects>

	<project>
		<name>Public Communication Award - University of Southampton</name>
		<date>June 2013</date>
		<description>The Public Communication Award was given to two students in the third year for a project to be self-standing and for use in recruitment on open days for the University. It came with an award of £1200 and <a href="projects/columbus.php">my robot</a> is used to convince students to come to Southampton. </description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>EMECS-thon Best Commercial Implementation</name>
		<date>February 2013</date>
		<description>
			The EMECS-thon is a 48 hour embedded system design marathon for students from Southampton University, University of Kaiserslautern and the Norwegian University of Science and Technology to partake in. Teams consisted of three members and the project can be anything within budget and has to use the MBED development board.<br/>
			My team decided on making a drum sequencer, cabable of playing a full bar of drums repeatedly and being able to be altered. The system also had prestored sequences that could be cycled through and variable tempo.
			<br/>
			The system used the MBED to do all the sequencing and audio playback. There was also an Atmel ATMega644P connected to control and read the bipolar LED and button matrix. The system, on a whole, worked well apart from the button debouncing and sailed Team Dan to success with rewards of Raspberry Pis.<br/>
			<br/>
			<object width="560" height="315">
				<param name="movie" value="//www.youtube.com/v/bfnQju70xNU?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0"/>
				<param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/>
				<param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"/>
				<embed src="//www.youtube.com/v/bfnQju70xNU?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="560" height="315" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"/>
			</object>

		</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>D4 Design Challange - Winning Team</name>
		<date>March 2012</date>
		<description>
			The D4 Design Competition is a prestigious event that occurs annually at the School of Electronic at Southampton. The competition is done over 3 weeks in teams of 6, and students have to build, design and test a given project. A certain amount of freedom was given to the students to make their own good (and bad) decisions. My years project was to build a fully autonomous football playing robot. The prize was £100 each from the sponsor Detica and I helped my team to success in claiming the prize.<br/>
			The project we were given was to make a football playing robot. The device should be fully autonomous, responding to light, sound and attempt to score a goal. <br/>
			My role in this was designing and building the AI to play football, extracting debug information from the system and coordinating the hardware aspects of the design. Though the end result was a little messy, and no football was ever played, the robot was a a result of 3 weeks of hard work and effort. <br/>
			<object width="560" height="315">
				<param name="movie" value="//www.youtube.com/v/eU7ikTZjma8?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0"/>
				<param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/>
				<param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"/>
				<embed src="//www.youtube.com/v/eU7ikTZjma8?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="560" height="315" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"/>
			</object>
		</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>Military Leadership Development Programme 1 (MLDP1)</name>
		<date>July 2011</date>
		<description>During my time in the Officer Training Core at Southampton, all cadets were taught the Leadership Development Programme. It is an introduction into the OTC, with basic weapons training, marksmanship, map reading, navigation and first aid amongst other things. My time in the OTC was great, getting to do all these activities, but I had to priorise and chose my studies.</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>Entry Level Rugby Referee (ELRA) Level 2 </name>
		<date>October 2010</date>
		<description>I qualified as a Rugby Referee when given the opportunity at University. Since then I have refereed many matches and been a key organiser of the Intra Mural League. Unfortunately, I no longer play rugby due to injury, but I like to keep with the sport none-the-less. </description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>PADI Open and Advanced Open Water</name>
		<date>September 2010</date>
		<description>I got both my diving qualifications in Malaysia in a week. My father, brother and myself went to Semporna, Borneo. I enjoy diving and have since been back to Malaysia to Kota Kinabalu, and Mexico for more diving. I enjoy it a lot and plan on doing more qualifications in the future.</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>Addison Award of Eningeering - King Edward VI Grammar School, Louth</name>
		<date>September 2010</date>
		<description>This award was given by my school to the Student moving on to the best Engineering degree after leaving year 13. It was a £250 reward for getting where I desired to be.</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>Duke of Westminster's Award - Nominee</name>
		<date>Summer 2010</date>
		<description>My Maths teacher and Cadet Commanding Officer Nominated me for this award, which assesses leadership in individuals, for my efforts and commitment within the CCF at school. I reached the final 40 nominees, but unfortunately made it no further.</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>Duke of Edinburgh Gold, Silver and Bronze Awards</name>
		<date>June 2009, 2008, 2007 respectively</date>
		<description>I undertook and completed all of the Duke of Edinburghs Awards. The main highlight of these were the expeditions. I got to explore the Lake District, Peak District, Wolds and Cheviots with friends living off what we carried on our backs.</description>
	</project>
	<project>
		<name>'Cello Grade 3</name>
		<date>2002 - 2008</date>
		<description>I played the 'Cello for 6 years and was part of Ensembles and Orchestras. I thoroghouly enjoyed playing this instrument and regret stopping. I hope to some day pick it back up.</description>
	</project>  
</projects>